所以我们已经学会了一些
So we already learned a couple of
非常重要的 HTML 元素并且已经能够
very important HTML elements and are already able
创建一个具有一些不错功能的漂亮页面。
to create a nice page with some nice functionality as well.
但现在是时候添加一些结构了
But now it's time to actually add some structure
到我们的文档和我们的元素。
to our document and to our elements.
现在让我们学习几个新的 HTML 五元素
And so lets now learn a couple of new HTML five elements
为了那个原因。
for that.
现在，当我说页面缺少某些结构时，
Now, when I said that the page is lacking some structure,
我的意思是所有这些元素
what I meant is that all of these elements
我们放在文档中的，
that we placed in our document,
简直就像一个个出现在这里。
they're all simply like appearing one after another here.
对？
Right?
他们之间并没有真正的区别。
They're not really like distinguished from one another.
特别是，
And especially,
它们不像以任何合乎逻辑的方式组合在一起。
they're not like grouped together in any logical way.
所以让我们通过创建来改变它
And so let's change that by creating
一些容器元素，然后将它们分组
some container elements, which will then group
这些元素在一起。
these elements together.
所以首先想到的一件事，
So one of the things that first come to mind,
这些链接在这里。
is these links here.
所以我们有所有这些链接，
So we have all of these links,
这种看起来像这里的页面导航，对吧？
and this kind of looks like a page navigation here, right?
所以页面导航通常是我们想要的，
So a page navigation is usually what we want,
当我们在页面顶部有几个链接时。
when we have a couple of links at the top of a page.
所以我们可以做的是指定一个特殊的元素，
And so what we can do is to specify a special element,
然后将所有链接放入该元素。
and then place all the links into that element.
我的意思是这个元素叫做导航。
And the element that I mean is called nav.
所以nav，代表导航。
So nav, which stands for navigation.
所以就这样，
So just like this,
现在这些需要缩进，
and now these need to be indentated,
或者至少应该是。
or they should be at least.
所以当我给它一个保险箱时，
And so when I give it a safe,
然后更漂亮地自动格式化。
then prettier formats this automatically.
现在这四个链接很好地分组
And now these four links are nicely grouped
在这里进入这个容器。
into this container here.
所以进入这个父元素，这是一个导航。
So into this parent element, which is a navigation.
现在，问题是当我们现在更新我们的页面时，
Now, the thing is that when we now update our page,
它看起来完全一样。
it does look exactly the same.
所以这里发生的一切
So all that happens here
是这个基本上像一个看不见的盒子一样被创造出来，
is that this basically created like an invisible box,
现在包含这些元素。
which now contains these elements.
好的。所以元素本身不做任何事情，
Okay. So the element on itself doesn't do anything,
它所做的只是将这些元素组合在一起。
All it does is to group these elements together.
而我现在明白了，
And I understand that right now,
它看起来并不直观或不合逻辑
it doesn't really seem intuitive or logical
这样做，但相信我，
to be doing this, but trust me,
一旦我们到达我们构建一些布局的部分
once we reach the section where we build some layouts
实际上也在下一节中，就在 CSS 上，
and actually also in the next section, just on CSS,
拥有所有这些不同的部分将非常重要
it will be very important to have all these different parts
在他们自己的容器内。
inside of their own containers.
好的。
All right.
所以看看我们的页面，
So looking at our page,
基本上，这是现在的导航，
basically, this is now the navigation,
这是标题。
and this here is the heading.
然后，我们在这里拥有所有这些，
Then after that we have all of this here,
这基本上是我们的帖子。所以我们的博客文章。
which is basically our post. So our blog post.
对？
Right?
所以这和上面的部分有点不同。
So this is kind of different than this top part.
所以这一切又是一篇博文，
So all of this is the blog post again,
这就像我们网页的顶部。
and this is like the top part of our webpage.
所以我们能做的就是对这个导航进行分组
So what we can do is to group this navigation
并将标题放入标题元素。
and the heading into a header element.
好的。所以让我们这样做。
All right. So let's do that.
所以这是另一个 HTML 五元素，
So this is another HTML five element,
这称为标题。
which is called header.
标题基本上意味着
And the header basically means
Web 文档的顶部，
the top part of a web document,
或者它也可以表示一些较小单元的顶部，
or it can also mean the top part of some smaller unit,
正如我们将在一分钟内实际看到的那样。
as we will actually see in a minute.
无论如何，这只是一个介绍
And anyway, this is just an introduction
到这五个 HTML 元素。
to these HTML five elements.
我们将更多地使用它们，
We will use them even more,
我会更多地解释它们
and I will explain them even more
当我们建立我们的大型网站项目时
when we build our big website project
稍后在本课程中。
a little bit later in this course.
好的？
Okay?
再说一遍，视觉上什么都不会改变，
So again, nothing will have changed visually,
但现在我们告诉浏览器，
but now we told the browser like,
“嘿，这里的所有这些都是我们的网页标题”。
"Hey, all of this here is our webpage header".
所以它是我们页面的顶部。
So it's the top part of our page.
然后所有这一切，正如我之前提到的，
Then all of this, as I mentioned before,
从这里开始，是页面的主要部分。
starting here, is the main part of the page.
在这种情况下，是一篇博客文章。
Which is in this case, a blog post.
还有一个非常常见的元素，我们可以在博客文章中使用，
And a very common element that we can use for a blog post,
是文章元素。
is the article element.
所以这是另一个容器元素，
So this is yet another container element,
但这次是一篇文章。
but this time it's one for an article.
而在这种情况下的文章实际上并不仅仅意味着
And article in this context actually does not simply mean
像这样的书面文章，
a written article like this,
但它也可以像现实世界中的事物。
but it can also be like things from the real world.
就像计算机是文章、笔或电话一样。
Like a computer is an article or a pen or a phone.
所以这些都是文章，
So all of these are articles,
如果我们需要用 HTML 来表示一台计算机，
and if somehow we needed to represent a computer in HTML,
那么一篇文章也将是一个很好的元素。
then an article would also be a good element for that.
好的？
Okay?
所以现在基本上，
And so now basically,
我们的身体只有两个直接子元素。
our body has only two direct child elements.
我们只有一个标题，我们有文章。
We only have a header and we have article.
这就是当我们查看我们的页面时，我们真正拥有的一切。
Which is when we look at our page, really all we have.
所以我们必须头球，剩下的我们都有，
So we have to header and we have all of the rest,
这是我们的文章。
which is our article.
所以现在它很好地放在了它自己的盒子里。
So that is now nicely placed inside of its own box.
现在，你可能会问一件事，
Now, one thing that you might ask,
“好吧，如果这些盒子，
"Well, if these boxes,
他们都什么都不做，
all of them don't do anything,
那我们为什么不把它们都称为导航，
then why don't we call all of them just nav,
还是全部标题或全部文章？”
or all of them header or all of them article?"
所以这个也可以是文章
So this one could also be article
页面上没有任何变化。
and nothing would change on the page.
对？
Right?
但是，我们不会为名为
However, we don't do that for something called
语义 HTML。
semantic HTML.
我将简要解释这意味着什么
And I will explain briefly what that means
在下一个视频中。
in the next video.
但现在继续更进一步，
But now continuing even further,
我们实际上可以在这里做更多的分组
we can actually do some more grouping here
在我们的文章里面。
inside of our article.
所以请注意我们是如何在这里拥有这种顶部的
So notice how we have kind of this top part here
的文章。
of the article.
所以基本上是标题，
So basically the heading,
作者在这里，
the author here,
还有图像。
and also the image.
所以这是我们文章的顶部。
So this is kind of the top part of our article.
然后在这里我们有内容本身，对吧？
And then here we have the content itself, right?
所以再次注意我是怎么说的，
And so once again notice how I said,
这就像文章的顶部。
that this is like the top part of the article.
所以就像这里
So just like this here
是整个网页的顶部。
is the top part of the entire webpage.
所以这意味着又来了，
So what that means is that here again,
我们应该使用标题元素来标记它。
we should use a header element to basically mark that up.
通过标记，我的意思是，
And by marking up, I mean,
基本上以更好的方式描述内容。
to basically describe the content in a better way.
正如我刚才所说，在文章内部，
So as I just said, inside of the article,
我们还想有一个标题。
we want to also have a header.
所以在那个标题里面，
So inside of that header,
应该有这个标题
there should be this heading,
这个作者图片，
this author image,
作者姓名，然后是这张图片。
the author name, and then here this image.
好的？然后关闭克它。
Okay? And then closing it.
现在这一切当然是，
Now all of this is of course,
也有点主观。
a little bit subjective as well.
所以对我来说似乎很合乎逻辑的事情，
So what seems very logical here to me,
对于其他开发人员来说可能不合逻辑。
might not be as logical for other developers.
但是，我认为我们刚刚在这里所做的，
But, I think that what we just did here,
直到此时，
up until this point,
对每个人来说都是合乎逻辑的，也很有意义。
is quite logical for everyone and makes sense.
再说一次，这里是文章的标题部分，
So again, this one here is the header part of the article,
有了这个，我们给出了我们的文章
and with this we gave our article
多一点结构。
a little bit more structure.
所以我们有标题，只有在那之后，
So we have the header and only after that,
然后是其余的内容。
then comes the rest of the content.
好的？所以这看起来已经很不错了，
Okay? So this is looking quite nice already,
但最后，如果我们在这里查看我们的演示，
but finally, if we look at our demo here,
实际上缺少一件事。
there's actually one thing missing.
事实上，有很多事情。
And in fact, there's multiple things.
所以我们还没有这些相关的帖子，
So we don't have these related posts yet,
但我们稍后会处理。
but we will take care of that later.
但我们在底部也有这部分。
But we also have this part here at the bottom.
所以这里是这个版权声明。
So it's this copyright notice here.
最后出现的这种内容
And this kind of content that comes at the very end
页脚就是我们通常所说的页脚。
of a page is what we usually call the footer.
事实上，正如你可能已经猜到的那样
And so there's actually, as you might've guessed
HTML 5 中的一个特殊元素。
a special element for that as well in HTML five.
所以，页脚，
So, footer,
然后让我们也关闭它，
and then let's close it also,
像这样。
like this.
现在让我们从这里获取文本。
And now let's grab actually the text from here.
实际上，它不在这里。
Actually, it's not here.
所以我们必须手动编写它。
So we have to just write it manually.
现在我们有两个选择。
And now here we have two options.
所以要写这段文字，我们可以创建一个段落
So to write this text, we could create a paragraph
然后把那个文本放在那里。
and then put that text in there.
或者我们实际上也可以在这里写文本
Or we can actually also write the text right here
进入这个页脚。
into this footer.
好的？这实际上就是我现在要做的。
Okay? And this is in fact what I will do now.
所以在这种情况下，这里不需要创建
So in this case, there is just no need here to create
还有一段，
yet another paragraph,
因为它将是唯一的孩子
because it's going to be the only child
无论如何，这个页脚元素。
of this footer element here anyway.
所以没有必要这样做。
And so there's no need to then.
所以版权，
So copyright,
现在你在这里看到这个版权符号，
and now here you see this copyright symbol,
我相信你知道。
which I'm sure you know.
那么我们如何创建它呢？
So how do we create that?
嗯，这就是所谓的 HTML 实体。
Well, this is something called an HTML entity.
所以实际上这是新事物。
So actually this is something new.
因此，让我快速向您展示我们如何做到这一点。
So let me show you quickly how we do that.
所以我们像这样写一个＆符号，
So we write an ampersand like this,
然后在这种情况下，
and then in this case,
我已经知道我想要的角色的名字了。
I already know what the name of the character that I want.
所以我可以开始写“副本”。
So I can just start writing "copy".
然后我可以在这里选择这个，
00:09:29,130​​ --> 00:09:32,873
或者我可以只写分号然后我们就完成了。
And so then I can select this one here,
or I can just write the semi-colon and then we're done.
所以这里的这个 HTML 实体就是代表这个的，这里是“C”。
So this HTML entity here is what represents this, "C" here.
好的？还有 HTML 实体的整个表格。
Okay? And there entire tables for HTML entities.
我的资源页面上有一个。
And I have one on my resources page.
我想我还没有提到那个资源页面。
I think I haven't mentioned that resources page yet.
但是在第一个课文中有一个链接
But there is a link to it in the very first text lecture
在第一节中，
in the first section,
以及我向您展示的 GitHub 存储库中
and also in the GitHub repository that I showed you
在第一堂课中。
in one of the first lectures.
在那里，你会找到一个页面的链接，
And there, you will find a link to a page,
其中包含所有这些 HTML 实体。
which contains all of these HTML entities.
但无论如何，我们会多谈谈这个
But anyway, we will talk a little bit more about this
无论如何，在课程的后期。
later in the course, anyway.
代码杂志。
The code Magazine.
好的。
00:10:16,616--> 00:10:19,033
所以写在未来，
Okay.
So written in the future,
给它一个保险箱，
give it a safe,
再一次，让我们重新加载，
And once again, let's reload,
正如我们所期待的，
and as we were expecting,
页面的视觉方面
the visual aspect of the page
还是和他们一开始说的一样。
is still the same as they mentioned at the beginning.
所以这些再次对将内容分组很重要
So these again are just important to group the content into
逻辑部分，
logical parts,
这对于语义 HTML 很重要，
which is important for semantic HTML,
以及使用 CSS 进行样式设置，
and also for styling with CSS,
正如您将在下一节中看到的那样。
as you will see in the next section.
说到语义 HTML，
And speaking of semantic HTML,
这将是我们下一个视频的主题。
that is going to be the topic of our next video.
所以我希望很快能在那里见到你。
So I hope to see you there very soon.